<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A new fairing for the merrily disposed:, or, The comical history of the famous Merry Andrew. W. Phill---. ; Giving an account of his pleasant humours, various adventures, cheats, frolicks, &amp; cunning designs both in city and country.</title>
            <author>Phillips, William.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1688</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 82 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 34 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A90667</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P2117</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R181776</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">43077558</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 43077558</idno>
            <idno type="VID">151644</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A90667)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 151644)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2269:3)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A new fairing for the merrily disposed:, or, The comical history of the famous Merry Andrew. W. Phill---. ; Giving an account of his pleasant humours, various adventures, cheats, frolicks, &amp; cunning designs both in city and country.</title>
                  <author>Phillips, William.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 3, [1], 60 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by J. Wallis, and sold by most book-sellers,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1688.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"This may be printed. Aug. 13. 1687. R.P."--Facing t.p.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Newberry Library, Chicago, Illinois.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Quacks and quackery --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Fairs --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>England --  Social life and customs --  17th century --  Sources.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Graham Hukill</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Graham Hukill</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="license">
            <pb facs="tcp:151644:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>This may be Printed.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Aug.</hi> 13. 1687.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>R. P.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:151644:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A New Fairing FOR The Merrily Diſpoſed: Or, the Comical HISTORY Of the Famous MERRY ANDREW, <hi>W. PHILL</hi>—. GIVING AN ACCOUNT OF HIS
<list>
                  <item>Pleaſant Humours,</item>
                  <item>Various Adventures,</item>
                  <item>Cheats, Frolicks, &amp;</item>
                  <item>Cunning Deſigns</item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>Both in City and Country.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed by <hi>J. Wallis,</hi> and Sold by moſt Book-Sellers. 1688.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:151644:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:151644:2"/>
            <head>THE INTRODUCTION TO THE READER.</head>
            <p>IF Merriment and Good Humour have their ſhare in thy Compoſition, I here preſent thee with an Entertainment whol<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>y J<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>coſe, which will tickle thy Spleen, yet raiſe no rebellious Paſſions with the moſt paſſionate Expreſſions; but leſt the biting of this <hi>Tarantula</hi> ſhould make thee Dye with Laughter, I have introduced a Crowder whoſe Harmonious Phancies are able to allay thy moſt Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>travegant Mirth. The Subject of this Diſcourſe was a Perſon who had <hi>Mercury</hi> for his Aſcendant in Conjunction with <hi>Venus,</hi> which render'd him Witty and Amorous, whoſe Power influenc'd his whole Life with the conſtant Intrigues of Love and Deſign.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:151644:3"/>
            <p>He was the famous DROLL of his Time, whoſe Reputation ſince has given Name to all his Succeſſors, and will Flouriſh in the World till Shows are out of date, and <hi>Bartholomew-Fair</hi> it ſelf ſwallowed up in Oblivion. His part was to Act, whilſt they who thought themſelves wiſer Men, only played the Fool. His Name is called <hi>Merry Andrew,</hi> I here give no Account of his Genealogy <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2+ letters">
                  <desc>••…</desc>
               </gap>r do I know what Relation he had to a Saint of that Name, more than that as you find in the following Account, he never quitted a Place but he left a Croſs behind him.</p>
            <p>As to the other Excellencies of his parts, beſides his Wit, I can ſay little to 'em, though I believe him not unskilful in <hi>Politicks,</hi> by the ſeveral Doubles he makes through the whole Courſe of his Adventures; and had he Liv'd in the Age when <hi>Caligula</hi> made bis Horſe a Conſul, he could not have miſſed of Secretary of State.</p>
            <p>I muſt Confeſs here are no eminent diſplayes of bis Courage, though I believe it was keen as Muſtard, of which we ſhould not have wanted ſome proofs, had he lived in a Country as fertile in Giants as other Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gions are faim'd: For he was a <hi>Tarlton</hi> upon the Stage, <hi>Roſcius</hi> in his Mimicks, in his plots a <hi>Guz<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man,</hi> and if the firſt Inventor of a <hi>Rat-Trap</hi> by the <hi>Cathinthians,</hi> had an <hi>Obelesk</hi> erected to his memory, his great Efforts of Wit deſerved a <hi>Pyramid</hi> for his Monument. In ſhort, he was a Perſon of <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:151644:3"/>thoſe prodigious Parts that I queſtion whether the Wit of Ten Men could compoſe a Foole like him.</p>
            <p>I ſhall be no longer thy <hi>Remora</hi> from Enjoying this great Cargoe of Wit and Humour, but take Leave in his Common Phraſe of Invitation:</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Pray Gentlemen walk in, for now we are ready to begin.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:151644:4"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:151644:4"/>
            <head>A New Fairing for the Merrily Diſpoſed, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <hi>WILLIAM</hi> the Subject of this Diſcourſe was Born in a Dark Entry, near <hi>Roſe Mary-Lane,</hi> the Houſe being obſcure his Birth was no ways Remarkable, more than that his Mother loſt a Father for her Child before he came into the World; But to avoid miſtakes, he was got in the ſtate of <hi>Wedlock.</hi> Nature ripen'd in him apace, for he was a Man of Art at Twelve Years Old, and could mend the Seam-rips of any mans habiliments: but that was but a Cloud to his inward Vertues, and ſoon was blown off. Now he's clim'd up to a Man, and only wants <hi>Buſineſs</hi> to ſhew him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, ſo that one Day being incumbred with Idleneſs, he reſolves to Divert his vacant Hours, but by what means he was doubtful, at laſt his thoughts running the Summerſet, he jumpt upon this Conceit, which was to
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:151644:5"/>go take the Air, or as the Old Wife ſays, <hi>walk a making Loyter-Pins,</hi> and Tempt For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tune for ſome Lucky Adventure, but could not pitch upon any particular place; by which you may gueſs he had no State-Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fairs in his head, yet at laſt he thought of St. <hi>James</hi>'s Park, <hi>Grays-Inn</hi> Walks, <hi>Lambs-Counduit</hi> Fields, being places where Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men ſometimes paſs o'r their idle hours, yet none of theſe did agree with his Inclina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, but ſhapes his Courſe for another part of the Town more remote, concluding with himſelf that the Borough of <hi>Southwark</hi> is the moſt proper Scene for a new Deſign, becauſe not far from the <hi>Bear-Garden,</hi> yet too near the <hi>Marſhalſey's.</hi> All Difficulties laid aſide, ever the Bridge he ſtalk'd, and with twenty gaſings and ſome few ſtops, he weathers the poynt of St. <hi>Margarets</hi> Hill, where on a ſud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded toſſing up his Eyes, they were catch'd by a M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>untebanks Stage, ſurrounded by a Regiment of ſuch Volunteers as himſelf, though they were of all ſorts Male and Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>male, amongſt which Crowd ſtood an Old Fiſh Wife, looking attentively towards the Stage, her Mouth as wide open as a gaping Oyſter barrel. <hi>William</hi> ſeeing her, ſtoops down and picks up two or three Oyſter-ſhells, then taking his opportunity, chucks
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:151644:5"/>them into her Mouth, well plumpt Cryes the by-ſtanding boys: ſhe ſtarts ſhutting her mouth, the ſhells ſet her Chops a bleeding, and before ſhe could put her tongue in a poſture to ſcold, he ſlips into another part of the Throng, but as he paſt along he ſpyes a gouty Shop-keeper, being a Crim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pling Spectator, and very careful of his Feet, yet <hi>William</hi> without any remorſe makes a falſe ſtep upon his Toes, at which he roars out, down tumbles <hi>Will.</hi> and ſhoots himſelf into a freſh quarter of the People, at that inſtant one comes Jack Pudding, roaring in his party coloured Cloaths, and his Flat Cap like a pyde Bull with his Horns ſaw'd off, where after a quarter of an hours impudent ignorance, ſpoken in all the abſurd and bal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derdaſh ways that could be, the famous Operator appears, after twenty ſower Faces and Iouſie ſhrugs, he begins to accoſt the Mobile: <hi>Goode People,</hi> and ſo runs on in a large Lying Oration; but when he came to the ſecond repeating of his Deſtructives Remedy, ſays he, <hi>I come for all your Goods,</hi> that's a Lye, ſays <hi>William,</hi> for half of us don't believe you. The Doctor replyes, Friend where doe you Live, that thus dares to interrupt me, why ſays <hi>William,</hi> I live in <hi>Whore and Baſtard Lane,</hi> next door to your
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:151644:6"/>Mothers, Sirrah, repli'd the Quack, your Manners is worn out, and can't be mended but at the Carts-Arſe; nor your Honeſty and Skill known ſays <hi>William,</hi> till you look through a wooden-hole <hi>Caſement</hi> for a Cheat, Sirrah, Sirrah, cries <hi>Jack Pudding,</hi> I'll ſilence you ſtrait; with that <hi>William</hi> ſteps to a Woman that ſold Dump<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, Mother ſays he, Mr. <hi>Pudding</hi> ſent me for a Dumpling, how ſhall <hi>I</hi> know that ſays ſhe? you ſhall ſee me deliver it ſays <hi>William;</hi> ſhe gives him one, he goes to the corner of the Stage, and when the Fool was in the height of his Ribbaldry, <hi>William</hi> hits him in the Mouth with a Dumpling, ſome of the hot Liquor flying in his Eyes; he howl'd, the Doctor ſtampt, there was Mirth and Vexation mixt to the general Satisfaction of the Spectators; when the Rabble had laught till their Follies were weary; the Fool ſwore, the Quack fretted, and both wiſh'd themſelves a hundred miles off: <hi>William</hi> in a by-corner had made a party of two-leg'd Brutes, ſuch as frequent thoſe Meetings, and came to the front of the Stage, where he demanded money for the Dumpling: The ſoberer ſort expected to have ſeen him been beaten, or ſeiz'd by a Conſtable but when the Mountebank
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:151644:6"/>threatned, <hi>Williams</hi> Crew bawl'd out, down with the Stage, down with the Stage, which the Doctor hearing, commanded them to keep Peace: At laſt, after ſeveral Extrava<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gancies more between <hi>William</hi> and them, the Doctor came to a parley and entreated a fair Accomodation, which after various Diſputes on either ſide was agreed to: <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> asked leave to mount the Bank, to be a Spectator there, which was willingly al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed. He behaved himſelf ſo wittily a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt them, with his ſly Tricks and blunt Jokes, that the Mountebank courted him to come and ſerve him; <hi>William</hi> ſtood not much upon Punctilio's, conſidering his pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Condition: A <hi>Bargain</hi> was ſtruck for ſeven ſhillings a week, and by that time ſeven weeks were run away, <hi>William</hi> had made himſelf famous, inſomuch that his Maſter parts with his old Fool, for a new Knave, and quitting that <hi>Station,</hi> betakes himſelf to the <hi>Countrey;</hi> where <hi>William</hi> is expected to unfold his moſt taking and waggiſh <hi>Parts,</hi> to make <hi>Robin</hi> and <hi>Joan</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſs themſelves, all which he did; and to add to their Delight, he made a Chriſtning, and invited all there preſent, and as many more as they could draggle along with them the next Market Day to it. The
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:151644:7"/>day came, a great Concourſe of <hi>Countrey Hicks</hi> and <hi>Megs</hi> appear, in the Crowd <hi>VVil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> eſpied the <hi>Hangman</hi> and a <hi>Serjeant</hi> of the Corporation not far from the Stage, he ſets a fellow or two and ſome of the <hi>Boys</hi> toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther by the Ears, then comes running out, and craves their help to part them, which they very readily did; for which kindneſs he invited them upon the <hi>Stage,</hi> where alſo was the Jaylors Wife, to ſee a ſtrange O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peration on a Childs <hi>Naturals.</hi> So they being all together, he ſtanding between them; takes one in one hand, and another in the other, and told the People that he had lived an <hi>Anabaptiſt</hi> ever ſince he came to his <hi>Maſter,</hi> and now being able to <hi>Anſwer</hi> for <hi>himſelf,</hi> made bold with theſe <hi>Friends</hi> to be his <hi>Goſſips,</hi> and the Name I take <hi>is Merry Andrew.</hi> With that there was a <hi>Shout,</hi> the <hi>Serjeant</hi> bit his <hi>Nails,</hi> the <hi>Hangman</hi> ſtorm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, the <hi>Jaylors</hi> Wife exalted her Voice, which the Rabble perceiving, they fell a pelting. <hi>VVilliam</hi> ſlipt behind the Cloth, the <hi>Goſſips</hi> tumbled off the <hi>Stage</hi> to eſcape the ſhowrs of <hi>Turnip Tops, Stones, Dirt,</hi> and what they could find to let them fly at them; the Fray being ended, <hi>William</hi> told them as they liked this, they might come the next day to the Goſſipping, and ſo took his leave of them.</p>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:151644:7"/>
            <p>Now you have ſeen <hi>William</hi> transform'd into <hi>Andrew.</hi> By the way of digreſſion, I am to tell you, the Doctor being a Man of Frailties, contracted a Friendſhip, or Marriage with a handſome accepting Sin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner; it was as Tying and Religious as <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drews</hi> Chriſt'ning, but you know Friend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip's a ſtrange Obligation. This ſhe Part<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner was Argouſly watch'd by our Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tebank, and for his farther Security, he en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyn'd her, whenever he was on the Stage (his Lodging being oppoſite to it) to ſtand at her window with a Vizard on, which ſhe perform'd with diligence: Yet ſhe was not ſo warm to him, as to be Ice to all o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers; for I muſt give you to underſtand, that <hi>Andrews</hi> many conceited Pranks had begot in her a likeing to his Perſon, as well as Parts, nor was he ſo dull or blind, but he could look through the Longings and Likeings of his titular Miſtreſs; nor did he intend to let the Game paſs by him, when he might ſtand in the Gap and ſtop it for his own Pleaſure. So without any further Circumſtance, he puts his Intentions in Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecution, and in few days found his Deſign take. She was abſolutely willing, and no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing but Conveniency of time and place wanting, which he undertook to compaſs.
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:151644:8"/>On a day when <hi>Andrew</hi> by his Officiouſneſs and Jollity of Humor, had drawn a vaſt Audience before him, taking the advantage of the Doctors being buſie in delivering out his Medecines, he whiſpers in one of the fellows Ears, I'm troubled with the Gripes, if the Doctor ask for me, tell him ſo; when ſtepping home he met the Maid of the houſe, being one whom he uſe to toy with, I'll lay thee a Shilling <hi>Doll,</hi> ſays he, that you don't ſtand a quarter of an hour look<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing out of our Window, with this Mask on; Done, cries <hi>Doll.</hi> not gueſſing at his purpoſe: Up he brings her, and when he ſaw his Maſter turn about to take a Packet, he gives his Miſtreſs a pull, and thruſt <hi>Doll</hi> to the Caſement. You may imagine the Came was not long a playing, they having ſo few Cards to deal. When done, <hi>Andrew</hi> repairs to the Bank with many a Crab-look, how now <hi>Andrew'</hi> ſays the Doctor, are thy Gripes off? Oh! Sir, ſaid <hi>Andrew, I</hi> thought one of my Puddings had been coming out, qut afer half a dozen ſtrains it ſhrunk back again into my Belly. <hi>I</hi> believe Nature was over charg'd, 'tis well <hi>Andrew,</hi> ſaid the <hi>Dr.</hi> it went off ſo quick. Now eave we them, and go back to <hi>Doll.</hi> ſhe being intent of winning her Weager, never minded what they did;
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:151644:8"/>when <hi>Andrew</hi> was gone, the Miſtreſs pulls <hi>Doll</hi> away, Oh! cries ſhe, <hi>I</hi> won't looſe my Shilling, are theſe your Tricks to ſave <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drew's</hi> Money? this is foul play, <hi>I</hi> will be judged by the Doctor elſe, which ſtartled the Lady ſo much, that ſhe flung the Maid a Shilling, and bid her pay <hi>Andrew</hi> if he claim'd it, if not, keep it for her ſelf. <hi>Doll</hi> hearing this, went away very well pleaſed.</p>
            <p>You have ſeen what a Progceſs <hi>Andrew</hi> has made at his firſt Entrance on the Stage of the World, Extravagance was his Intro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duction, and as wildly he purſu'd it through the continu'd Courſe of his adventurous Life; for having debauch'd his Miſtreſs, his Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petite grew dull, freſh matter muſt be found for his changeable <hi>Genius</hi> to work upon. It ſo fell out, that the Landlady where they lay had a Daughter tempting enough, yet not over laded with Virtue, as it was ima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gined by <hi>Andrew,</hi> her Name is <hi>Iſabel.</hi> To her <hi>Andrew</hi> lays <hi>Siege</hi> to her, but it was beat off with much loſs of time: Then, as Envy enters old Women, and ſo they become <hi>Witches:</hi> ſo Revenge ſteps in, with his new ſlighted <hi>Paſſions;</hi> he caſts about how to put a Trick upon her, that the Town might ring of her Miſcarriage. And as he was meditating in a low Room
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:151644:9"/>about the Project, <hi>Isbel</hi> paſſed by the Win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dow, whom he calls to him, and very gravely entreated her to faſten his Crevat-ſtring: ſhe came to the Window, putting in her hands on each ſide the Bar, he catcht faſt hold of her Arms, and with a Nap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kin he had in his Hand, ty'd them toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther within; then putting his hand over her, pluckt up her Coats, and pinn'd them to her Back, ſhe ſtrugling to get looſe diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered bare both fore and aft. Away got he, and in comes a <hi>Stage-Coach</hi> with <hi>Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vellers,</hi> who lighting and ſeeing <hi>Isbel</hi> ſtand ſo, thought ſhe was to have ſuffered the <hi>Laſh:</hi> One of the Maids <hi>coming</hi> out, eſpy'd her, and runs and hides her Poſteriors, whilſt another within ſet her at Liberty. The Boys grinn'd, the Women ſmil'd with a caſt-down look, the men as you may gueſs <hi>laugh'd</hi> out aloud, and you may eaſily <hi>imagine</hi> that all the Effects of <hi>Rage</hi> and <hi>Fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry</hi> reign'd in our thus affronted <hi>Iſabel:</hi> But the firſt Effects are <hi>brought</hi> forth in Tears, the common Expreſſions of womens Grief; in this Flood of Dolour, her Sweet-Heart <hi>coming</hi> in, was ſurpriz'd at the running over of the <hi>Springs,</hi> her Eyes; whom ſhe per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiving <hi>through</hi> her watry Proſpect, nothing but Death could be her Comfort. <hi>Andrew</hi>
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:151644:9"/>ſtanding privately above in the Gallery, ſaw their <hi>Meeting,</hi> and throws down a Chamber-Pot upon them both, and then conveys himſelf away ſo clandeſtinely, that he was not diſcovered. They immediate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly <hi>wiping</hi> themſelves, begin to enquire who it was that had ſerv'd them ſo: No body was ſuſpected, nor any one owning it, it ſhew'd that one Croſs was the forerunner of another; they withdrew into a by Room, to have a full <hi>Hearing</hi> of their former Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fortunes, and to conſider who this was that had water'd them with the Piſs-pot; after many <hi>Arguments</hi> between them, they vow a Secret <hi>Revenge</hi> to <hi>Andrew;</hi> for you muſt know, the Lover was Valiant in nothing but in Proteſtation of his Affections to her, and that he might the better apply ſome Comfort to her afflicted Spirits, he (with a bundle of Oaths to be true) obtains a Grant of <hi>Enjoying</hi> that Trifle, which igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant young Folks think a <hi>Bleſſing,</hi> but find a Croſs all their life time after; an hour hence in the Hen-Rooſt is thougth the moſt convenient time and place, where the Bat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle of Love and Luſt may be fought, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides it would be then dark, for they durſt not truſt themſelves in the Houſe. <hi>Andrew</hi> having been ſmartly imployed with a Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:151644:10"/>Fellow about the Tooth-Ach, and finding the dull Clod of Earth ſoftned for any Impreſſion; firſt pulls out the Tooth, then tells him to be ſure never to have it again, is to have a hole bored through his left Ear: The Dunce contented to have it done on the <hi>Stage</hi> for a famous Operation. <hi>Andrew</hi> to make the People merry, and do the Fool not much hurt, whips a hot Iron through his Ear, waſhes it a little, then puts as big a Padlock on't as he could get the Haſps in; telling he muſt appear with it ſix Market Days, and never leave it till the time's expired, which he promiſed to do accordingly, and ſo <hi>Andrew</hi> diſmiſſed him. Being afterwards invited to a Jovial Dames Houſe, to meet ſome mad Wenches at a Supper; he to encreaſe the Feaſt, comes home, and thinking of his Landladies Poul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey, reſolves to make more room in the Rooſt, by picking out a Couple of fat Pullets, which he thought would be accep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table to the Company he was to meet: Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king an Excuſe to go to the Houſe of Eva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuation, in order to his being more near to the Covey he was to plunder; a ſmall time it was, but enough for him who wanted a Load, more than to lighten himſelf. He was forc'd to mount a Ladder at the end
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:151644:10"/>of a Barn joyning to the Garden, to accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſh his Ends: up he creeps, and goes, care<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully and ſoftly in, lays hold of a Fowl, and jerks off her head, and croſſing over to feel for another, tumbles down; the firſt thing he felt was a bare Thigh of <hi>Iſabells,</hi> ſhe durſt not Crye out, nor <hi>Andrew</hi> make a Noiſe fearing he ſhould loſe his Hen, he groaping, found that the Beaſt with two Backs had been made there; and by the mutter of their Voices knew 'twas <hi>Iſabell</hi> and her <hi>Enamorado.</hi> Down got he and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moves the Ladder, and away he highs to the Gang that waited his coming, leaving the Affrighted Couple to pearch there till Morning; but by the help of the Oſtler coming for Hay they got down; and ſtole into their Lodging undiſcovered; the Secret remaining in his Diſcretion which for that time did not come out.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Andrew</hi> has now forgot where he left his frighted <hi>Iſabel,</hi> and is wholly intent to the preſent frolicks. The <hi>Muſick</hi> played, the Laſſes are tugg'd, the Men drunk, and the Married Women jolly, all turn'd into a Chaos and Confuſion of Humours. At laſt the dreadful ſound comes, <hi>What's to Pay? Andrew</hi> ſtarts up, Not a Man pays a farthing here but me. A Loving Soul crouds half
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:151644:11"/>a Crown into his hand, a Half-Seas man's Wife treads on his Toes and palms him Two Shillings, Another beckons him into a Corner, where he gives her a Token of his Kindneſs, and ſhe pop for pop, pops him a George, She being the only ſweet Soul amongſt them all. The Men ſcorning to ſuffer him to Treat them and their Wifes, throw down the Reckoning.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Friends</hi> (Cryed he) <hi>you may come to repent of this haſty parting with your Money;</hi> No not they, they Anſwer'd with an Oath. <hi>Andrew</hi> gathers up all the Money, <hi>Well Friends</hi> (ſays he) <hi>I'll have the honour of paying the Houſe,</hi> with all their hearts, he put a health about, and goes down Stayrs, and marches off with all the Money. They beginning to be Cloyd with Drink, Enquire for <hi>Andrew,</hi> but he is not to be found, Well, come, let us go then, <hi>Who pays?</hi> (ſays the Hoſteſs) Mr. <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drew,</hi> replyed the Women, <hi>He is gone</hi> (ſays ſhe) <hi>and not payed a Peny:</hi> At that word there was a general ſilence through the whole Aſſembly; a thing to be wondred at conſidering what was done, and what they had been doing. But after divers angry poſtures amongſt the Men, Women, and Maids, of ſcratching their Elbows, Buttocks and Flancks; a ſmart Laſs that had a Vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:151644:11"/>Itching for <hi>Andrew,</hi> broke out of the Dumb Aſtoniſhment, and ſays, this is a Device of his, to make us Laugh another Time, let us free our ſelves now, and cry quittance with him when we next get him at advantage. The motion took, by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon the Women were too Drunk to ſcold, and the Men beſotted with the Surprize. So a Common-Purſe was made, the <hi>Hoſteſs</hi> Diſcharged, and they went ſtaggering home to Sleep, and never Dreamt how they ſhould come by their Money again.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Andrew</hi> went to his Quarters, the Oſtler being his great Crony, he up and told him what he had done; and they were both pleaſed with the Slur which he had put upon them.</p>
            <p>In return of <hi>Andrew</hi>'s Relation, the Oſtler acquaints him with the Condition he found <hi>Iſabel</hi> and her Unfortunate Friend in, and what Room he lay: The Devil ſtraight enters <hi>Andrew,</hi> and out he goes; At the Gate lived a Butcher who had killed ſome Sheep for the Market four miles off, and had hung One up by the Gambrells at his Door. <hi>Andrew</hi> fetched a Trunk which he uſed to ſhoot Peaſe with at the Boys, puts that through a hole into the Shop, and blows out the Candle; then takes the whole
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:151644:12"/>Sheep on his back, and carries it ſoftly up into the young mans Chamber; where he was faſt a-ſleep in his Bed, he lays the dead Sheep by him, and goes his way into the next Room, where the Oſtler and he ſit down to watch what would become of the Mutton. The Spark waking finds ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing lyes heavy by him, Joſtles it, but could not make it ſtir, putting out his hand to feel what it was, feels the cold skin of the flead Sheep, when whipping in his hand again he falls to Prayers, ſhivering and ſhaking, but turning about to cover his Head, hits his hand againſt the Noſe; <hi>Ah Lord!</hi> cryes he, ſtark Dead! and fell a Groaning moſt Dreadfully. Over joy'd with this Account, away goes <hi>Andrew</hi> and the Oſtler, and leaves him in this pitious Condition.</p>
            <p>At Break of Day <hi>Andrew</hi> goes down, where he heard the Butcher Curſing and Swearing, That ſome Damn'd Rogue had ſtol'n a whole Sheep from him. <hi>Andrew</hi> putting his Face into the moſt diſſembling Figure he could, ſeemingly Pitties him, though inwardly tickled with this Exploit, <hi>Neighbour</hi> (ſays he) <hi>come along with me, I had a certain Viſion in my Sleep, and me thoughts I ſaw your Mutton lie on a Bed in our Inn. Let's go ſee</hi>
               <pb n="17" facs="tcp:151644:12"/>up Stayrs, they went, where without any difficulty <hi>the loſt ſheep was found;</hi> the Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant half ſtew'd in his own Liquor was examind'd, the Fright keeping him ſhaking, rendred him the more ſuſpected; upon which in down right terms he was charg'd with the Theft. <hi>Andrew</hi> upbraids him, the Oſtler carries a double Face, and both ſweetens and pinches. Before this was all made out and clear'd the Doctor removes his Station to the Borders of <hi>Scotland,</hi> where <hi>Andrew</hi>'s Familiarity with his <hi>Miſtreſs</hi> and many other Rogueries were diſcovered, for which he was turn'd away, and left to juggle himſelf to <hi>London</hi> again if he could.</p>
            <p>His Maſter and he being parted, the <hi>Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thern</hi> Air being ſomewhat too <hi>cold</hi> for his Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitution, he was reſolv'd to change the Climate, preparing to Steer his Courſe <hi>Eaſtward,</hi> to the Metropolitan City of <hi>London;</hi> which had been the place of his Nativity, and former abode: and accordingly over night took leave of his Landlady, intending next morning to be makeing forward on his Journey. Sitting by the Fire and caſting his Eyes downwards upon his Carriers, he ſpies a poor fleeting Sole which by violent Storms and foul wea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther was juſt wrackt from the upper Lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther;
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:151644:13"/>with that, fetching a deep ſigh, and conſidering the many weary ſteps he had to make before he ſhould arrive at his wiſh'd for Poſt, he thought it fit that ſuch Faults ſhould be amended; with that after having deſired his Landlady to fetch a Flagon of Ale, he prayes the Maid of the Houſe to carry his Shoe to the Coblers, which ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly was done, ſhe ſpeaking to him to under lay it, which he very decently perform'd.</p>
            <p>Having taken leave of his Landlady, and paid for his Drink, he retires to his Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber to conſult with his Pillow, what courſe he ſhould take for money to defray his Travelling Charges; having now but ten pence half penny left. Coming into his Chamber he begins to pack up all his Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliments, which indeed neither required Trunk nor Box to hold them; ſince a large Pocket, or a ſheet of Paper would have incloſed all: he having little elſe, but ſome ſmall Pots of Medicines which he had pil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fred from his Maſter, thinking that at one time or another in his Travels he might with them deceive ſome ignorant Country Boor. He then going to Bed, where ly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing all night and dreaming of his <hi>Pilgrimage:</hi> In the Morning he wakes, and getting up,
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:151644:13"/>prepares himſelf for a March: In comes the Coblers Boy, deſiring Money for his Maſter for mending his Shoes; Prithee, ſays he to the Boy, tell me what is it that thy Maſter hath done for me? Indeed Sir ſays the Boy, I cannot tell, then pray go back to thy Maſter, and deſire if he intends to be paid, to fend me a Bill for what; the the Cobler immediately hearing of his An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, poſts to the Clerk of the Town, and tells him that <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> was going from his Maſter, and wou'd not pay him for his Work, unleſs he ſent him in a Bill; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore humbly intreats him, to be ſo kind to draw it up for him. which the Clerk as willingly perform'd. The Bill immediate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly was ſent to <hi>Merry Andrew,</hi> who reading over, found it to be to this Effect.</p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <head>Mr. <hi>Andrews Bill.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <row>
                     <cell role="label"> </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <abbr>
                           <hi>l</hi>
                        </abbr>
                     </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <abbr>
                           <hi>s</hi>
                        </abbr>
                     </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <abbr>
                           <hi>d</hi>
                        </abbr>
                     </cell>
                     <cell role="label"> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>For an Underlay</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>01</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>For <hi>Sprigs</hi> to faſten the <hi>Heel</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>½</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell role="total">In all</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>01</cell>
                     <cell>½</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <pb n="20" facs="tcp:151644:14"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Andrew</hi> conſidering with himſelf, and ſmiling, Orders the Boy to bid his Maſter come to him, for he did not uſe to pay Money without an Acquittance and Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge in full, which before he paid it he would have: The Boy preſently fetches his Maſter, who got the Clerk to accompa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny him: no ſooner did <hi>Andrew</hi> ſee him, but he tendred down the three half Pence on a Table, and demanded a Diſcharge in full, which the Clerk writ, and the Cobler ſign'd; now, ſaith <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> let's have Coblers Law, he that hath receiv'd money call for his Pot, at which the Clerk and all the People fell a laughing, that the Cobler was beaten at his own Weapen: the Cobler did generouſly call for his half dozen, and the Clerk likewiſe, for the merry Conceit, where <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> got a large Mornings Draught for his Three half Pence, and ſo ſet forward on his Journey.</p>
            <p>The Day proving fair, the Sun diſplay'd his Beams, which made <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> glad the Cares of his Journey being pretty well thrown out of his Head by the Coblers large mornings Draught; he put on a pace, where coming down a Hill into a pleaſant Vale, he over took a Man, whom he no ſooner ſpyed, but he made up to him with
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:151644:14"/>full Sail: <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> accoſts him after the old Phraſe, <hi>Well over taken Frinend, how far Travel you,</hi> Towards <hi>York</hi> replies he, at which <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> was Glad, that he had ſo luckily met with a Companion, who ſteer'd the ſame Courſe with him. They marched on about a Mile further, where on the ſide of a Hill, ſtood a very pleaſant Seat, which no ſooner the Man eſpyed, but he quickned his pace, and mov'd on faſter than ordinary, when coming to a Lane which turn'd up to the Houſe, he made a ſtop, and putting his hand under his Coat, unbuckled, and took off a <hi>Green Bag,</hi> which <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> ſuppoſed to have been <hi>Writings;</hi> but he no ſooner had opened it, but out peeps the head of an old decay'd Fiddle, which no ſooner <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> ſaw, but his Heart Caper'd in his Belly. <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> made up to the Fidler, and demanded of him whether he intended to ſtay at that Houſe; yes, replyed the Fidler, <hi>I</hi> intend to hazard here, and it may be I may make a penny to bear my <hi>Nights Charges;</hi> and if you will ſtay with me, I ſhall be glad to Accompany you to your Journeys end: Agreed, ſays <hi>Merry Andrew,</hi> and moving forwards, the Fidler began to tune up his Inſtrument; which was no ſooner heard,
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:151644:15"/>but out comes the Servants of the <hi>Houſe;</hi> with that, <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> brisks up, <hi>Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men,</hi> ſays he, will you have a Leſſon of good Muſick, or ſee any Agility of Body, Gentlemen Flipflaps or Summerſets? No replyed the Servants, our Maſter is not at home, but if you will give us a Tune or two, we will give what the houſe will afford, Victuals and Drink; content cries <hi>Merry Andrew,</hi> Rub up your Guts Fiddler, whilſt I ſhew them a Trick for Love. <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> having ſhewed them ſome Tricks which cauſed their Laughter, they rewarded him both with Meat and Money, which the Fiddler ſeeing, grew angry, and repented he had taken a Partner more ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king than himſelf; but as they walked forward, <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> gave him an equal Dividend of what he had got, which made up the Breach.</p>
            <p>Their Stay here having retarded their Journey, Night was drawing on, when they came to a ſmall Thatch'd Village, and and inquired if there were ever an Alehouſe; the People anſwered that <hi>was</hi> it five Mile to any houſe or Town.<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Say you ſo reply'd <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> to his Comrade, who indeed was almoſt tir'd: Come let's walk as far as we can. They had not Travell'd above
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:151644:15"/>two Miles, but the Night came on ſo faſt, that they grew fearful of looſing their way: <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> looking about, by chance ſpies a large hay Stack, ſcituated hard by a houſe, he conſiders with himſelf whether he ſhould venture to make that his <hi>Habitation,</hi> and ſleep like a Pig in Peaſe Straw, or Travel on till they found ſome Inn; but the poor Fiddler being weary with his days March, perſwaded him to ſtay, and embrace that Airy Tenement.</p>
            <p>Being both agreed, they began to undermine the Stack, and there tumbled in like Swine into a Sty: They had not lain above an hour, but <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> hears a Door clap, and a great Dog bark, which put the poor Fidler and he into a breathing Sweat, thinking that if they ſhould be found there, they would opprehend them for Rogues deſign'd to rob the <hi>Houſe;</hi> with that <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> peeping from under his fringed Canopy, eſpied a Maid Servant, who was ſprinkling the G<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>aſs with Natures watring Pot; which no ſooner ſhe had ended, but turning her round<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ſhe met her Fellow-Servant and Sweet Heart, who taking her about the Neck, after his Ruſtick manner of Salutation, tumbles her upon the Graſs, where finiſhing the work of Generation, <hi>He made poor Andrew a Pimp in his own Defence.</hi>
               <pb n="24" facs="tcp:151644:16"/>The Wench being well pleaſed with what ſhe had then rereiv'd, invites her Friend into the Dairy, which <hi>was</hi> a little <hi>way</hi> from the Houſe, where ſhe makes him to partake of a <hi>Bowl</hi> of Curds and Cream, having provided Sack, Sugar, and ſeveral other Toys to heighten the Appetite of her Amorus Lo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver. <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> over hearing of this nightly Banquet, reſolves to partake of their Cheer, and accordingly creeps from the Eaves of his Caſtle, and moving ge<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>y towards the Dairy; ſpies a Sheets which he thought very convenient for his Deſign j and accordingly made uſe of it, tying the Top with a Strieg in the faſhion of a <hi>Shrowd,</hi> he put in upon his <hi>Head,</hi> and thinking <hi>with</hi> himſelf that his Phyſiognomy was not al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>together ſuitable, he remembred a piece of Chalk he had in his Pocket, to prevent the ſlipping of his Dancing Pumps; having ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken it out, and rubb'd his Face <hi>with</hi> it, he <hi>go</hi>'s eaſily to the Milk houſe Door, where he found them <hi>Laughing and in a Heighth of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riment:</hi> when of a ſudden he and the Fid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler made a hideous Noiſe, which done, <hi>Merry Andeew</hi> immediately enters, <hi>whom they</hi> no looner ſaw, but the one Scriek'd, the other Trembled, and flying to the Houſe in this Aſtoniſhment, left <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> in
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:151644:16"/>full Poſſeſſion of all the Dainties, where having filled his B<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>lly, he repaired to his Thatch'd Chamber. Day-light coming on, and caſting his Eyes about, he ſees the Houſe which appear'd to belong to a Perſon of no ſmall Quality. Immediately he poſts the Fidler to the Door, who after a Leſſon, giving good Morrow to the Worſhipful, he had balf a <hi>Crown thrown down out of the Window,</hi> which they lovingly embraced, and ſo marched <hi>onwards</hi> of their Journey, leaving the Lovers with Fear and Trem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bling.</p>
            <p>They had not Travell'd above ſix or ſeven Miles, but <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> began to be troubled with a grumbling in his Guts, whether <hi>with</hi> Cold got in his Lodging, or over loading his Stomach <hi>with</hi> Cheeſe <hi>Curds,</hi> I <hi>know not;</hi> but he reſolves with his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rade, that the next Alehouſe they came to, ſhould ſupply them with Brandy or ſome warm Liquor to eaſe his Grief: Whilſt they <hi>were</hi> thus diſcourſing and <hi>walking</hi> lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurely over a Common, they diſcern'd a Houſe, which they made up to, imagining it muſt be an Alehouſe by the May Pole ſtanding at the Door, and even as they thought ſo it proved; for <hi>when</hi> they came at it, they found both Meat and Drink.
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:151644:17"/>Entring the Houſe, they found none but a lone Woman, whom <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> ask'd if ſhe had any Brandy in the Houſe, ſhe replyed yes; having call'd for a Gill of Brandy, they ſate them down by the Fire, <hi>Andrew caſteng his Eyes up to a hanging Shelf,</hi> he ſaw a Pye <hi>well</hi> fregiht with Beef, Pork, and ſuch other Delicacies as the Countrey did afford: his Brandy having warm'd his Stomach, and eas'd him of the Gripes, he begins to conſider with himſelf, that the Brandy and the Walk together had got him an Appetite, and therefore Contrives how, or <hi>which way</hi> he might ſupplant the Woman of her Pye, and not have it found out till his departure.</p>
            <p>After having toſſed off two or three <hi>Gills</hi> Betwixt his Comrade and himſelf, with the Civil Aſſiſtance of his <hi>Hoſteſs,</hi> he deſir'd her to fetch him a Flagon of Beer, ſaying, too much Brandy <hi>was naught,</hi> tho' indeed he did not think ſo, only to get her out of the Room, till he could manage his Inge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nious Contrivance. The Woman being gone into the Yard to <hi>waſh</hi> her Pot, <hi>Merry Andrew whips out his Knife, calling to the Fid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler,</hi> Uncaſe, Uncaſe, <hi>The Fidler drawing his Fiddle out of the Caſe, holds the Caſe under the hanging Shelf, whilſt</hi> Andrew <hi>with his Knife
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:151644:17"/>cuts all the bottom Cruſt round, and lets the Meat drop into the Caſe.</hi> The Hoſteſs coming ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtily up Stairs from drawing the Beer, <hi>Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Andrew</hi> hearing her, runs haſtily to the Door, where making a falſe Step at the Threſhold, tumbles the old Woman over, breaks the Jug, ſpills all the Drink, and breaks the Old Womans Shins into the Bargain. Whilſt that he and the Hoſteſs were lamenting each others Misfortune, the Fidler had planted his Caſe under his Coat, having clear'd the Magazeen, and leſt the bare Walls of the Cruſty Caſtle ſtanding upon the Shelf. The old Woman howl'd, <hi>Andrew</hi> look'd ſad, down went her Stockins to look of her Shins, up goes <hi>Merry Andrews</hi> Sleeves, to look of his <hi>Elbows:</hi> At length, <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> pulling out ſome old Relicks of his Maſters ſhop, applies a Plaiſter ta the Old Womans Shins, and ſo pretendingly another to his own Elbows. The old Hoſtels being glad that ſhe had ſo luckily met with Medicines for her Cure, agrees with <hi>Andrew for what he would have to leave Salve to Cure the Wounds he had wilfully made.</hi> At length they comply, where the Shot is paid with old decayed Drugs, with that <hi>Andrew calls for a Pot to drink his Hoſteſſes good Health,</hi> the Fidler plays, <hi>Andrew</hi> Sings,
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:151644:18"/>when ending their Liquor, they bid Adieu to their <hi>Hoſteſs,</hi> leaving her to Plaiſter up all her Grievances. The Remainder of the Day following they ſpent in pleaſantly <hi>Laughing</hi> at each others Contrivance, and their late excellent <hi>Humours, with which they they had ſo neatly gull'd their Hoſteſs.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Sun growing low, they drew nigh unto a Town, which <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> inqui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring what place it was, found it to be a Copporation, where they had formerly had a Stage; with that applying himſelf to an Inn where his Maſter had lodged, the Tapſter Greets him kindly, and they fell to drinking ſmartly; in the interim, in a Parſon comes riding into the Inn, whom the Tapſter ſhow'd into a fair Room, and acccording to the uſual Cuſtom, <hi>asked him what he would be pleaſed to drink, or what he would have to Supper:</hi> but he proving to be one who lov'd <hi>Eating</hi> better than <hi>Drinking,</hi> bids the Tapſter bring him a <hi>Single Mug</hi> of Ale, and get a Shoulder of Mutton for his Supper. The <hi>Tapſter</hi> haſted to the Kitchin and tells them his Pleaſure, which was ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly fulfilled.</p>
            <p>The Mutton being laid to the fire, the <hi>Tapſter</hi> return'd to his old Acquaintance <hi>Andrew,</hi> where they ſate drinking and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſing
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:151644:18"/>of former Paſſages, till the <hi>Tap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter</hi> was called to lay the Cloth, which he readily did. <hi>Supper being brought up,</hi> the Parſon <hi>with ut the tedious Ceremony of a large Grace,</hi> falls to famouſly. The <hi>Tapſter</hi> ſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing behind, <hi>wiſh'd him half Choak'd,</hi> fearing he ſhould have none left to Accomodate his old Acquaintance. The <hi>Raging</hi> of his Stomach is at length appeas'd, and Meat enough left to have ſatisfied his Deſire: But the Parſon forgetting the Scripture Phraſe, <hi>takes as well care for his Breakefaſt to Morrow, as his Supper to Night;</hi> and orders the <hi>Tapſter</hi> to ſet the Meat upon the Cup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boards head in his Chamber, over which <hi>bung a very Large Looking-Glaſs.</hi> The <hi>Tapſter</hi> would fain have made an Excuſe that he <hi>might</hi> in ſome Meaſure oblige his <hi>Travelling</hi> Friend <hi>Andrew,</hi> telling the Parſon that the Room was haunted with Cats and Rats, and that if the Meat ſtood there he wou'd not have a bit left by <hi>Morning:</hi> But the Parſon <hi>grew</hi> more miſtruſtful, <hi>believing no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing could be ſafe out of his ſight, and orders it to be ſet there,</hi> which was accordingly per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form'd; and ſpeaks to the <hi>Tapter</hi> to bring him up another <hi>Mug</hi> of Bear, and then he would prepare for Bed.</p>
            <pb n="30" facs="tcp:151644:19"/>
            <p>The <hi>Tapſter</hi> makes haſte to his old <hi>Friend Andrew,</hi> and acquaints him with the Buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, Pox on't, crys <hi>Andrew,</hi> I have a <hi>Trick</hi> at fingers ends ſhall help us out, take a long piece of <hi>Pack-Thread</hi> and make a ſlip Nooſe, and when you <hi>go</hi> in with the Drink ſlip it about the Knuckle Bone, and draw the <hi>String</hi> out of Doors after you: The <hi>Tapſter</hi> took his Frinds Advice, and <hi>earrying</hi> in the Beer made an Excuſe to the Cupboard, where <hi>fixing the Project,</hi> he goes out of the Chamber, leaving the <hi>Parſon to take his Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tural Reſt.</hi> Down he <hi>goes</hi> to his Friend, where they <hi>Laugh</hi> and <hi>Drink,</hi> the Muſick playing till towards <hi>Midnight;</hi> At length, <hi>thinking of the Supper they had laid a Trap for,</hi> they went ſoftly to <hi>the Parſons</hi> Door, <hi>where Andrew</hi> pulls the <hi>String gently,</hi> Rattle goes the Diſh, Cat, Cat Whore! crys the <hi>Parſon,</hi> which caus'd them to <hi>Laugh</hi> extremely. At <hi>length Merry Andrew gives the other Pull,</hi> down comes the Meat and Diſh and all; <hi>which the Parſon hearing,</hi> takes the Bed-Staff and flings it furiouſly at the Cat as he <hi>Imagin'd; Rattle goes the Looking Glaſs,</hi> he hearing the Glaſs broke, creeps into Bed, where <hi>he</hi> lay as quietly as a Man without a Soul. The <hi>Tapſter</hi> and <hi>Andrew fell to the Meat,</hi> when <hi>having</hi> Eaten what <hi>they</hi> would, they knaw
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:151644:19"/>the Bones and lay them at the Door. Day<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>light <hi>coming</hi> on, the <hi>Tapſter</hi> haſtens to the <hi>Parſons</hi> Chamber, when coming to the <hi>Door,</hi> he crys, hey day what work is here now? <hi>I. I,</hi> replys the <hi>Parſon; Tapſter</hi> had I taken <hi>thy Counſel all had been well:</hi> When <hi>coming</hi> into <hi>the</hi> Room <hi>he</hi> ſpies <hi>the Looking-Glaſs broke, hey day why how comes this?</hi> Indeed good <hi>Tapſter</hi> I did it; prithee know of thy Miſtreſs the Reckoning, and what ſhe muſt have for <hi>the</hi> Glas, <hi>which the Tapſter</hi> as readi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>did; and <hi>brought this</hi> Account. <hi>A Shoulder of Mutton and a Looking Glaſs; with Bread and Beer; Twenty nine Shillings.</hi> The <hi>Parſon</hi> paid the Reckoning, and call'd for his <hi>Horſe;</hi> but never ſtaid to drink. The Maſter <hi>Laugh'd,</hi> the Miſtreſs ſmil'd <hi>that her</hi> old faſhioned Glaſs was turned into a new one; the <hi>Tapſter</hi> Applauded <hi>Andrews</hi> Contrivance, and gave <hi>him Money</hi> at parting; to help to his Journeys end.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Andrrw</hi> and his Friend Crowder <hi>go</hi> on <hi>their Progreſs</hi> in ſearch of new Adventures; and it <hi>happened</hi> on a Sundays Evening, (for <hi>they</hi> made no ſcruple of times or Seaſons) <hi>that they</hi> met upon a Green a merry Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany of Lads and Laſſes, and a Fellow <hi>play<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> on a Fiddle, made of <hi>the Shoulder Bene</hi> of a <hi>Horſe:</hi> You cannot imagine, it ſoun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:151644:20"/>as well as a <hi>Cremonia</hi> Violin; bet <hi>much</hi> better <hi>than</hi> a <hi>Frying Pan</hi> which they us'd to ſettle Bees with: When <hi>Andrew</hi> had view'd <hi>the</hi> Gamballing Medly of Cat and <hi>long-Tail, he thought</hi> it proper to put in for a Snack of <hi>this</hi> voluntary Mirth, and cuſtomary Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>garies. So throwing himſelf on his <hi>Hands</hi> walks into <hi>the Forreſt of Ignoramus; they ſeeing</hi> a Reverſed Mortal were ſtruck with Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration, but when they heard his ſtrilling Companion to exalt his <hi>Trehble,</hi> they were <hi>then</hi> abſolutely <hi>weather</hi> bound; and could not tell what poynt of <hi>the Compaſs</hi> they ſhould put <hi>their</hi> Leg forward in. <hi>The Scraper</hi> of <hi>the</hi> Village was <hi>then</hi> of no uſe, their old pleaſure was now a pain; and with all poſſible <hi>Celerity</hi> they begin to tune their Legs to thoſe new <hi>Harmonious</hi> Notes they were ſurprized with. As the Minſtril <hi>was charming,</hi> ſo was<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
               <hi>Andrew</hi> no leſs taking with <hi>his Frolick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſome</hi> Demeanour. A ſhe Animal of a <hi>Dairy</hi> Maid was unreſiſtably captivated, <hi>ſhe purſu'd</hi> him through all the <hi>Hops</hi> and Jumps of his Antick Poſtures, and at laſt proſtrates her Affection; by conſenting that he ſhould that Night not only take part of her Bed, but take poſſeſſion of her <hi>Tenement</hi> of Fleſh; ſo ready a <hi>Compliance</hi> he willingly embrac'd: So home he Accompanies her, and to bed
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:151644:20"/>they go: No body need trouble their <hi>heads</hi> to know what <hi>they</hi> did <hi>there,</hi> but may <hi>expect</hi> what will come forty weeks after, tho' a ſhorter time will determine <hi>this</hi> Matter; for before <hi>Morning,</hi> he Glutted with what <hi>he had never ſought,</hi> took the Advantage of Wakefulneſs, and dreſſing <hi>himſelf,</hi> ſeiz'd <hi>all her</hi> Holy-Day Furniture <hi>as free Prize, leaving her naked to cover her Shame with the Apron of Repentance.</hi> His Companion in the mean while had plaid himſelf into a conſiderable Fortune, and was much troubled for <hi>Andrew</hi> to come and participate. It was not long before <hi>he had his</hi> Wiſh, <hi>and then they conſulted their</hi> future Safety, which was lodg'd in <hi>the</hi> moſt expeditious Eſcape they could make: It was reſolv'd to change <hi>the Countrey,</hi> as <hi>well</hi> as <hi>the</hi> Air of that narrow Village.</p>
            <p>'Tis a general reciv'd Opinion, that Men indiſpos'd have their Intervals of Eaſe and Pain; and ſo have <hi>theſe Travellers</hi> the Mu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tability of Time and Chance, <hi>for what they have irregularly got:</hi> we ſhall ſee it as extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vagantly ſpent in pleaſing their own <hi>Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours.</hi> In few days <hi>all</hi> is expended in <hi>Brandy,</hi> and the worſt Evil Women; ſo that a new World, or a new <hi>Trade,</hi> muſt preſently be found out to ſtop the Raging Furies of their intolerable Wants: But tho' <hi>Andrew</hi> wants
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:151644:21"/>Subſiſtance, <hi>he</hi> wants no Confidence; <hi>eſpecially</hi> when <hi>he is thruſt on by the Extremity of Want,</hi> nor is it long before he meets with a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veniency to improve his <hi>Talent in a ſmall Village.</hi> In their way, as nothing could be a wrong Rode to them but the Gallows, or the Whipping Poſt; he chopt into the company of ſome Countrey Exciſe Men, who were much taken with his Gay and Drolling <hi>Humours,</hi> with whom he attain'd Admittance at a <hi>Town</hi> Dinner. In <hi>the beginning</hi> of their <hi>Tooth Combat,</hi> his Aſſociate, the <hi>Crowder</hi> being pinch'd by that curs'd <hi>Vulture Hunger,</hi> lays his Wits abroad, and boldly ventures upon this Deſign. There was a Window to the Room they eat in, which look'd into a Garden, <hi>where one had hung his Cloak, Crowder</hi> gets a Ladder, thinking if he could not carry the <hi>Cloak</hi> off <hi>Smoothly,</hi> it ſhould paſs for a Jeſt; ſo [up <hi>he</hi> aſcends to the Window, at <hi>his firſt Approach</hi> Andrew ſpies <hi>him;</hi> you damn'd Rogue cryes <hi>he,</hi> will <hi>you</hi> ſtill haunt me? So he took a Shoulder of Lamb and threw at <hi>his Head,</hi> and after <hi>that</hi> a penny Loaf, <hi>then</hi> ſtarting from the <hi>Table, ſnatches a Bottle of</hi> Wine, <hi>and threw that too:</hi> the Fidler fell down and pull'd <hi>the Cloak</hi> after <hi>him: The Company</hi> buſied to appeaſe <hi>Andrew,</hi> minded not any <hi>Thing</hi> that paſt,
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:151644:21"/>whilſt <hi>the</hi> Fellow poſted away <hi>with what</hi> he had got.</p>
            <p>You muſt know <hi>this Tool of Muſick</hi> was pawn'd to his <hi>Landlord</hi> for paying <hi>the Taylor</hi> for mending his tatter'd <hi>Breeches,</hi> which <hi>he</hi> inſtantly redeems; and haſtens back again to <hi>the Houſe:</hi> by <hi>the way be turns his Coat,</hi> and ſmuts his Face, and as ſoon as <hi>he</hi> Enters, ſtrikes up a Flouriſh: and cries, <hi>Gentlemen, will you have any Muſick? Andrew glad</hi> of this Opportunity <hi>falls a ſhaking of his Heels, the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany</hi> growing pretty warm, were eaſily in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duced to <hi>the Matter;</hi> and admire the many merry and unlucky Pranks of theſe two unknown <hi>Companions. Amongſt other Frolicks they contrive a New Way of drinking a Health,</hi> with taking a <hi>Table</hi> a little bigger than a Joynt Stool, and turing up the Frame, the <hi>Fidler</hi> was to begin: <hi>Andrew</hi> ſeeing a <hi>bundle</hi> of Pitchforks makes ready for <hi>Hay</hi> Seaſon; takes four of them, and by the help of four more in the <hi>Company,</hi> fixes the Forks at the four <hi>Corners</hi> of the Frame, and ſo <hi>lifts</hi> up the <hi>Table</hi> with the <hi>Fidler</hi> in it <hi>like a Pulpit;</hi> the Glaſs went about, and every Man was mounted in his <hi>Turn:</hi> This Sport produced great <hi>Laughter,</hi> at which the <hi>Landlady</hi> of the <hi>Houſe</hi> having a mind to know the <hi>Cauſe</hi> of it, came in, <hi>Andrew</hi> had it preſently in his
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:151644:22"/>
               <hi>Head, Oh Miſtreſs</hi> I ſays he, you are come to Crown the Invention; up you muſt go, ſhe Laughs and refuſes; but the Gueſts <hi>being high Flown</hi> nothing <hi>will</hi> excuſe her <hi>Compliance</hi> with them in that Frolick. In ſhe is put, and then hoyſted up, the <hi>Crowder begins a Health with a ſtamp,</hi> ſhe was to end it; ſo when it came to her (ſhe being a <hi>Sociable Hoſteſs</hi>) did as they did, gave a <hi>ſtrong ſtamp,</hi> at which the Lid of the <hi>Table</hi> came off, and ſhe ſlipt through with <hi>Coats</hi> up to her Armpits, and tho' ſhe made great ſpeed to acquit her ſelf, yet there was a <hi>plain Diſcovery.</hi> Now he is the <hi>Only Man who can ſhew the moſt Extravagant Fancy; Hats, Periwigs and Coats</hi> are thrown about, at the ſame time the Muſick is very generouſly rewarded, who in return of <hi>Thanks will ſhew them one Trick more: he</hi> takes <hi>ones Hat,</hi> anothers <hi>Perriwig,</hi> a thirds <hi>Coat,</hi> and ſo fantaſtically <hi>Accouters Himſelf,</hi> but <hi>when</hi> he had Mimict or Scha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ramoucht as long as he <hi>thought</hi> fit, he very ſmoothly play'd himſelf down Stairs, and then goes the back <hi>Way</hi> to his <hi>Lodging, where</hi> he undiſguiſed himſelf, and by turning his <hi>Coat</hi> the right ſide <hi>outward,</hi> is become in <hi>all</hi> Appearance another Man. The Blades he left are full of Expectation what the Event of his Conceit will be; at laſt weary
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:151644:22"/>with expecting of his Return, Inquiry was made, but no ſuch Man could be heard of. <hi>Andrew</hi> Rants, they Curſe, none ſuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pecting <hi>That they knew one another.</hi> Night coming on Every one betook himſelf to his Journey home, <hi>The Cataſtrophy proving not agreeable to the firſt part of their Jollity.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The next Project is to diſincomber them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves of the Goods they have got by ſlight of hand and foot, their Landlord hearing them grumble; <hi>I can't carry the Cloak:</hi> Says one, <hi>Nor I the Cote</hi> ſays t'other, <hi>Would we had Money for them,</hi> ſay they both, proffers to buy them, if they would part with 'em upon reaſonable Terms. Their Demands are accepted and the money laid down. Early in the Morning they left the Town, and the great Road; venturing upon a by<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way to prevent any purſuit after them, and as they met with various Paths they chang'd their way, and after an hour or two's labour in ſweat and dirt, and often wiſhing and looking for any houſe where they might refreſh their Craving Stomachs, they could diſcover none, but the neareſt thing that Humane Creatures frequent is a Wind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mill, to which they repair with all the Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gour their fainting Spirits would allow
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:151644:23"/>them; Groaning, Puffing and Curſing, they arrive at the Thiefs Caſtle, expecting no Succour there more than to be inſtructed in their way to the neareſt Village. At the foot of the Ladder or payr of Stayrs, they called Miller, and then honeſt Friend, though at the ſame time they knew 'twas a Lye, yet adding Diſſimulation, their con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant Companion, and what all the World knows is a proper and uſeful Partner to the Cheating Trade of a Miller, they Repeated <hi>Hey from above there! Good Man!</hi> but all in vain, ſays <hi>Andrew</hi> it may be the Thief's run away from his Caſtle; ſo by joyn'd Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent they Aſcend the Lader, where upon the Platform they find the Governour of the Windy Meal Box aſleep on his Back, <hi>they 'jogg'd him, pull'd him, ſpoke to him, no Anſwer was made, nor ſign of Waking;</hi> but prying nearer into the Buſineſs he proves to be knock'd down by ſome potent <hi>Liquor,</hi> and there lies like a Hogshead of dead Beer. Let him Snore on ſays <hi>Crowdero,</hi> I am for making a privy Search what his Whirligigg houſe affords and in walks he: <hi>Peeping about, he firſt ſees a Houſewifes</hi> Cake <hi>brought there by ſome who gave him Toll of her Corps, and he excuſed them of their Meal:</hi> And now finding a Stone Bottle, to which he claps
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:151644:23"/>his Noſe, took a luſty Draught of Bran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy; the other lays his <hi>Hand</hi> on a Wooden Can, upon whoſe Lid lay a ſlice of boil'd Bacon, they both fell to, and with a rave<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nous Dexterity devour'd all Eatable, or fit to Drink, and between them fill the emptied, Bottle with Piſs; but their Roguery could not end here. A new Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſultation is held what is to be done with the intranced Beaſt; <hi>Miſchief never wants quick Invention,</hi> they take a Sack and draw under his Back, then tie the two Ends to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether, and faſten them to a Rope, which hangs down on purpoſe to draw up Sacks of Corn to Grind, or let down the Meal; <hi>they</hi> pull him a good <hi>way</hi> from the Stairs, then turning the Beam they lower him within Eight or Nine Foot of the Ground, and poſt away, leaving him to ſwing himſelf awake.</p>
            <p>You may think it was not the eaſieſt Lodging that ever he had, therefore could not remain there long aſleep. In a ſhort time he awakes, and cannot tell what he ſhould be a doing, he could not call it Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding nor going on Foot; in a little ſpace he found out <hi>what Poſture he was in,</hi> but <hi>how he came ſo, was his greateſt Wonder;</hi> he can
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:151644:24"/>ſee no body to call to, nor did expect any body to come there that Day, by Reaſon he had in the Morning taken his Work in for the <hi>Morrow:</hi> his Truſs began to hurt and he thinks, that his hanging by another part <hi>would be now his beſt Remedy.</hi> Some<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing muſh be done and that quickly, the Knot could not be untyed, <hi>wherefore he puts his Hand into his Pocket, and draws his Knife, and without further Conſideration cuts the Rope,</hi> down comes he Neck and Shoulders, and but that he was reſerved for a worſe Fate, muſt undoubtedly have broke his Crag, where we leave him crawling up the Lad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of his Deſtiny, and return to our <hi>Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vellers,</hi> who are falling out about what they ſhould have for Dinner, before they knew where to have it. By and by they reach a Town, and into a <hi>Houſe</hi> goes <hi>Andrew,</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceals his Animoſity till his Belly was full, and they gone to Bed: <hi>His Companion falls faſt aſleep whoſe Pocket he Ranſackt, and in the Morning with the Truckle Bed-Cord, ties him down in the Bed, takes out his Fidle, cuts out the Belly piece and Shits in it,</hi> ſo macrches away reſolving now to ſet up once more for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf.</p>
            <pb n="41" facs="tcp:151644:24"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> being parted from his crowding Companion, takes hearty Cou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage, reſolving with himſelf no longer to looſe his time in hunting the Wild-Gooſe Chaſe; bethinks himſelf doing ſomething Meritorious, whereby his Name may be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come famous to Poſterity. <hi>In purſuit of which, he reſolves with himſelf that at the next Countrey Town he ſhould arrive at, to take upon him to be a Man of Learning, Reſolving all man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner of Aſtrological Queſtions whatſoever:</hi> when climbing up to the <hi>High</hi> Rope of Inven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, to find ſome lofty Title ſutable and and agreeing with his new Profeſſion, his Brains running the Maze, for ſome far-fetch'd Pedegree; at length he ſtiles him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf by the Name of <hi>Andreugio Guillielmo Philippo</hi> the Italian Fortune Teller. Being come to the eaſie Top of a Neighbouring <hi>Hill,</hi> looking earneſtly about, he deſcries a pleaſant Village, Scituated by a Rivers ſide not many Furlongs diſtance, when ſitting down upon a Bank, he cleaned his Shoes, and combed his Hair, intending that as he had changed his Name; to change his Countenance too, and ſo put on Gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vity.</p>
            <pb n="42" facs="tcp:151644:25"/>
            <p>Being come into the Town, and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred his Hoſteſſes Acquaintance, he breaks to her his Intentions, deſiring to know of her, <hi>whether a Stranger and a Traveller, might find a Reception ſuitable to his Art and Parts;</hi> ſhe candidly delivered her Mind, telling him, that a Man of his Worth and Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, could not miſs of Practice anſwera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to dignity of Quality; and withal thinking it might prove very Advantageous to her ſelf, to promote his Intereſt. Our new made Fortune Teller, finding him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf ſo kindly Entertained by his Landlady, and that he had ſo fair a Proſpect of Succeſs in his new Intrigue, calls for Liquor plen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifully, <hi>knowing</hi> the only way to get Eſteem amongſt the Countrey people, is to ſhew himſelf Liberal in his Quarters. Having drunk himſelf to a reaſonable pitch, he begins to grow Amorous, pretending a more than ordinary Kindneſs to one <hi>Iſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bella,</hi> with whom he was Kiſſing and Toy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing all the Evening, till ſuch time as the <hi>Hour grew ſeaſonable for Reſt.</hi> Having over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perſwaded the Wench with his <hi>Canting Rhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torick,</hi> to make promiſe that ſhe would come to bed to him, aſſoon as the <hi>Houſe</hi> was cleared of all the Gueſts, and het Aunt and the reſt of the Servants were in
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:151644:25"/>bed if he would leave the Door upon the Latch; upon which our new Conjurer quietly betook himſelf to his Apartment, and is with eager Expectation waiting for his Miſtreſs.</p>
            <p>But his Brains being ſomewhat ſtupified, <hi>partly with</hi> Drink, <hi>and partly with his</hi> Days <hi>Travel,</hi> he had not been in Bed long before he <hi>fell</hi> into a Slumber; the young Buxom Laſs who was earneſt for the Enjoyment of her new Lover, lifts gently up <hi>the Latch,</hi> and prving into the Room perceiv'd him to be aſleep, <hi>and immediately returns to liſten if her Aunt and the reſt of the Family were in Bed:</hi> She leaving open the Door, think<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing then ſhe might enter with leſs Noiſe or Suſpition, in the interim, a great Grey-Hound, whoſe Cuſtom was to make uſe of Chairs, Stools, Beds, or any eaſie Lodg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, rather than lay his thin gutted Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſe on the Floor, walks ſoftly into the Room: <hi>Our Friend being between ſleeping and wak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing calls to mind his Miſtreſſes Promiſe, and crys out, Ah my Dear!</hi> and Addreſſing himſelf to the Bed ſide, the loving Cur according to his natural Kindneſs does Lick and Tongue this hot Braind Lover, when claſping his Arms about his Neck, he crys, <hi>My Dear!
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:151644:26"/>my Delight! let me Imbrace thee once in my Arms, to Bed, to Bed my Love, loſe now no time;</hi> the fawning Beaſt expected not all this Court<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip to his wonted Lodging, but leaping upon the Bed, he Embrac'd him faſt about the Middle, when finding his Tallons ſcratch'd his Poſteriors, he Shriek'd out, and upon the Noiſe, the Dog left the Chamber, having taken down the Courage of his Leacherous Bedfellow. <hi>Andrew trem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles and quakes, and thinks it is a Judgment up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on him for pretending to that he underſtood not;</hi> but the Noiſe hearing, Alarm'd the <hi>Houſe,</hi> up comes the Maid with a Candle, Where? Where? Looking to the Door he ſees his <hi>frighted Companion</hi> ſhaking his Tail, the Maid demanded the Cauſe of all the Noiſe, no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing replys the <hi>Conjurer,</hi> but a Familiar that I uſed to have converſe with me about things that are loſt grew a little troubleſome to me; the harmleſs Maid departs to bed, <hi>Levuing</hi> him and his hrt Zeal to be finiſhed ſome other time.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Next Morning the Landlady</hi> begins to publiſh and applaud the <hi>Art and Learning</hi> of her Gueſt; his Name was no ſooner ſpread through the Town, but a Gentleman com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to bait at that Inn, as he was Travel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:151644:26"/>the Rode, had ſtoln from him a neat Setting Dog, who making his Complaint to the Landlady, telling her he did not care what it coſt him, ſo he could but re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover him; gave preſent order to have him Cry'd throughout the Town, but could hear no Tidings of him.</p>
            <p>Our Aſtrologer <hi>having been in the Yard to Eaſe himſelf</hi> and returning up a back pair of Stairs to his Chamber, he heard a Buſtle in an adjoyning Cloſet, peeping through a hole, he ſaw ſomething ſhagged, <hi>but what ſort of Creature he could not plainly diſcern.</hi> Going into his Chamber, he could not diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern any way into the Cloſet, <hi>till caſting his Eye under the Bed, he perceived the Bottom of a Door, where removing the Bed, he found an old Trunk, wherein lay muffled this loſt Setter;</hi> which he no ſooner ſaw, but poſts down Stairs, where he found the Landlady and her <hi>Travelling</hi> Gueſt hot in Diſpute about the Dog, and which was the moſt probable way to retrieve him: The good Woman Recollecting her Memory, calls to mind her <hi>New Lodger,</hi> informing the Gentleman <hi>of his great Art and Skill in Aſtrology,</hi> and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covering of things loſt, immediately he was call'd, and after the Gentleman had paid his
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:151644:27"/>Reſpects to him in a Glaſs of Wine, he told him that if by his Art he could diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vet where his Dog <hi>Tray</hi> was, he <hi>ſhould be Nobly Rewarded:</hi> he embraced the Offer, <hi>and going into his Chamber with Pen, Ink and Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per he preſently erected a Scheme, and making a Circle in the Room,</hi> he Thrice waved his <hi>Wand</hi> round his <hi>Head;</hi> ſpeaking ſome hard words he had ſtolen from the Bowels of an old Play; which no ſooner was perform'd, but Elevating his Voice, he calls out, <hi>Canis; Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nis, Canis,</hi> being ſo well learn'd to un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtand what was Latin for a Dog; this long Ceremony was ended, he deſires the <hi>Gentleman</hi> to withdraw, telling him in few <hi>Hours</hi> the Dog would come flying into the <hi>Houſe.</hi> When <hi>Releaſing the Dog from his cloſe Confinement,</hi> having taken good notice of the Room whereto the Gentleman was withdrawn, he crept up to the Top <hi>of the Houſe,</hi> and finding the Chimney of the Apartment, having provided a large Cracker for this his Lofty Deſign, whilſt the <hi>Gentleman ſate below</hi> in the <hi>Height</hi> of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riment, over<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ov'd he ſhould once more be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold his dear <hi>Game Companion,</hi> he gave fire to the Cracker, which he had tyed to his Tail, and tumbled him howling down the Chimney; <hi>his ſhaggy Carcaſe</hi> beat down all
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:151644:27"/>the ſoot into the Room, which ſtruck ſuch a Terror into the Beholders, that they all Cryed out, believing he had raiſed a <hi>Devil</hi> he could not lay again. The poor Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man being a man of no Extraordinary Cou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage, through Panick fear let his Brains fall into his breeches, that, what with the ſtinking of the Soot, and the Excremental favour from the Gentlemans ſhort hoſe, they thought the Dog had come from <hi>Pluto</hi>'s Territories.</p>
            <p>The Storm being allayed, and the ſmoky Clouds vaniſh'd, the Gentleman departed, rewarding liberally, and highly applauding this ingenious Artiſt.</p>
            <p>His Fame now rung loud in the Ears of all the Inhabitants, the young Fry came tumbling far and near, ſome for loft Spoons, Bodkins and Thimbles, Butlers for Plates and Napkins, ſtol'n at Feſtivals; Young ſilly Maids to know their Sweethearts, Widows for Husbands, Batchellours for Wives, which they expected could be done by this famous Negromancer.</p>
            <p>He being in the height of his New-Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferment, hears of a Quack or Mountebank,
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:151644:28"/>
               <hi>Who was coming to invade his Territories,</hi> which ſet his Brains to work, running to flip flap one over another, to invent ſome Stratagem whereby he might Expoſe this New Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſter to the Scorn and Contempt of the Rout.</p>
            <p>The next Market-day appears the Stro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling Doctor, who had ordered a Stage to be Erected, which was ſupported by Two Buffet-Stools, which our Conjuring Artiſt no ſooner ſaw, but he went immediately to the Tapſter, deſiring him to help him to an Ingenious Lad, that would attend him that day for his Credit ſake, he being re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved to Face that <hi>New <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pſtart;</hi> who re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commended to him a witty pregnant Boy, who was not long in learning his Leſſon, and fit to undertake ſuch an Enterprize.</p>
            <p>The fam'd Aſtrologer being Mounted on a Steed, borrow'd of his Landlord, rode into the Market place, attended by his Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant, when approaching the Stage, where he beheld his Rival with Eyes full of Indig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation, thus deliver himſelf to the People.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>I am Gentlemen a Traveller, Born in the Country of</hi> Hungaria.</p>
            <pb n="49" facs="tcp:151644:28"/>
            <p>Yes replyes our Aſtrologer you look like a <hi>Hungarian Fellow</hi> indeed. <hi>What ſawcy Jack are you?</hi> anſwers the Doctor, <hi>who dare Affront me, knowing neither my Learning nor Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority. I am that famous Artiſt who Cured the Biſhop of</hi> Munſter <hi>of the Toothach, and by Vertue of this my rare Elixer, the Great Cham of</hi> Tartary <hi>of the Cramp in his Tongue.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>As for your Learning and Authority I knew not</hi> replyes <hi>Andrew, how I ſhould underſtand them, by reaſon you never had any, and as for your Medi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cines they are all a Cheat, and you a Quack; And that I will prove, for know Gentlemen That I am that rare Artiſt which I will make good before you all. For if he be that famous Artiſt which he ſays he is, Behold I will fall down and Worſhip him, but if that honour does belong to me, he then ſhall fall before me.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>His new Servant having perform'd his part, and fixt a Rope to the Doctors ſtall, tyes the other end to his Maſter's Horſes Leg, and gives the ſign. The Conjurer rides round, down comes the Stage with the Doctor, at which the People ſhouted, the Boys hollowed, and with a loud Applauſe Extoll'd the Conjurer, whilſt they pelted the other into his Inn with Carrets and
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:151644:29"/>Turnip Tops. <hi>Andrew</hi> is thus become pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lickly Eminent, with the Ruine of his Competitor, <hi>and though highly Extoll'd in the Opinion of the People,</hi> an After-Clap from croſs Fate fell upon him, to the utter Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>credit of his Miſterious Art of Fortune-Telling.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>A Perſon paſſing through the Town at the ſame time, diſcovered him to the Multitude for a Noto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torious Cheat,</hi> many <hi>Laugh'd</hi> at the ingenious Prank he played the Doctor, but finding out his Roguery, the Countenance of their Pleaſure was quickly changed, and he forc'd to fly the Town.</p>
            <p>As tis impoſſible for a Man to live with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Food, ſo it was for him to live without Invention: As he was <hi>Travelling</hi> the Rode, he met with a <hi>good</hi> Countrey Houſe-Wife <hi>having</hi> upon her Arm a Basket of Apple Pyes, Cuſtards, and ſuch like <hi>Things</hi> as pleaſe Children; he very jocondly ſteps to her, and ſays, <hi>Good Woman what have you in your Basket?</hi> Pyes Sir ſays ſhe, with that <hi>turn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> up the Cloth he handles the Womans Commodities, and by <hi>Slight of Hand</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veys one into his Pocket, then pretends to the Woman her Pyes were not good, ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:151644:29"/>to her, they are Tuff, and hot well baked: I'll ſhew you a Pye I <hi>bought at the laſt Towns End,</hi> and with that falls a Eating the pilfer'd Pye, <hi>giving</hi> her to bite, to ſee if ſhe liked it.</p>
            <p>The Woman <hi>being too Credulous,</hi> was ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſily perſwaded to allow what he ſaid; he ſeeing her a <hi>good</hi> likely Woman, was re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved his Deſign ſhould-not end ſo, but taking her by the <hi>Hand,</hi> tells her that if ſhe would go to the next <hi>Houſe</hi> to drink, he would take a Taſte of her <hi>Things.</hi> The Woman being willing to vend her <hi>Goods,</hi> goes with him, when coming to the <hi>Houſe,</hi> he finds it well furniſhed with Children, <hi>takeing hold of the Basket,</hi> he <hi>gave</hi> every <hi>Child</hi> one, ſaying, I will be your Chapman, thank you Sir, cryes the Woman, this is a <hi>Lucky Morning,</hi> ſhow us a Room, and cries <hi>Andrew,</hi> and bring us in two Pots.</p>
            <p>The Woman of the <hi>Houſe being mightily</hi> taken with the <hi>Good</hi> Nature of her Gueſt, <hi>brings</hi> them a Raſher of Bacon alſo; He by his Inſinuation got an abſolute Conqueſt over their <hi>Good</hi> Opinions, and tipling to a pitch he <hi>taking the Advantage of his Landla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies blind ſide, wriggles</hi> himſelf into her Ac<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>quaintance,
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:151644:30"/>and whilſt ſhe ſtept into the Pantry to carry away the Bread, he fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows his Project, <hi>making</hi> the Pye Woman meaſure his Rowling Pin. The Loving Landlady <hi>coming</hi> in, he pretends to make water, where <hi>going</hi> forth of the Doors, he leaves the poor Pye woman, and his Landlady equal Partners in the Reckon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing. So haſting away he got that Night <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o <hi>London,</hi> where he could not long want a New Subject for his unwearied Fancy to work upon.</p>
            <p>Being Arrived at <hi>London,</hi> it is not to be diſputed but that he continues as much a <hi>Vagabond</hi> as ever, and Rambles into all Quarters of the Town to find an Anvil to Forge ſome new <hi>Roguery</hi> upon; and very opportunely a <hi>Stratagem</hi> offer'd it ſelf, <hi>which was,</hi> he <hi>caſting</hi> his Eyes upon a Fellow who ſtood <hi>peeping</hi> behind a Porch; began to conſider what was his <hi>Buſineſs,</hi> he was not <hi>long</hi> in <hi>Apprehending</hi> what his watchful <hi>Poſture</hi> meant, but without any more ado, in his <hi>Thoughts</hi> pronounc'd him a Bayliff, as he really was. He did not take much time to deliberate what wrs to be done, but ſteps to him, and ſays Friend, you have loſt; what? replies the Setter, your Man, ſays
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:151644:30"/>
               <hi>Andrew,</hi> through the Backſide of the — and there paus'd, what through the <hi>Miter?</hi> cryes the fellow, I, ſays <hi>Andrew,</hi> his Maſter is gone with him, Not Mr. <hi>Hedgley,</hi> Yes, yes, ſays <hi>Andrew,</hi> and I know where they are gone, pray (ſays the Dog) go Friend with me to the Plaintiff and tell him what you know, and ſaw; wirhal my heart ſays he, I want Employment and conſequently Money, you ſhall be rewarded then ſays the Setter.</p>
            <p>Away they go to a Tavern hard by, and there the Bayliffs Man tells what <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drew</hi> had ſaid, the Plaintiff tells him, if he will aſſiſt the Officer in taking this Man, he ſhall have half a Piece; <hi>Andrew</hi> told him, it was but a ſmall price for Bone-ſetting and Plalſters, for that muſt be Expected, the Perſons being <hi>Dangerous Men.</hi> Ther'es a Crown ſays the Plaintiff, and when you have finiſh'd I will not be ungrateful.</p>
            <p>O but Sir, ſays <hi>Andrew,</hi> a Whore and a Bailiff are Callings alike; and neither of 'em is well performed if they have not Money in hand; 'tis the Legs of their Cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, for Souls they have none. Upon this the Plaintiff advanc'd the other Crown,
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:151644:31"/>Well Sir, ſays <hi>Andrew</hi> I'll pledge you— a mouthful of food would do well in the End.</p>
            <p>After he had well liquor'd his Throat, away they Trance about their Man-Eating. <hi>Andrew</hi> was an Exact Geographer of all the By-Alleys, and ſecret paſſages in that part of the Town; ſo leading them thro' many intricate Turnings, he plants them in an Alehouſe, with telling them he will make private inſpection, and if yon doubt me, ſee what Houſe I enter: though they are naturally Credulous, they believe him with ſo much Caution that a Centinel is placed upon him, which he is not inſenſible of, which made him more Circumſpect and quick in his diſpatch.</p>
            <p>Through the Yard they were to paſs ran a deep Common-Shore, the Sink of the Neighbouring Houſes of Office: He un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>props the Door which lay over it, and when he had done, gets over on a poſt that lay croſs, and comes out again, They are ſafe lodg'd ſays <hi>Andrew,</hi> and when you ſee me in again, and give the Sign by pulling off my hat two or three times, ran in with all ſpeed, the quicker and thicker you come
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:151644:31"/>the more ſure it will be. With that away goes he, and no ſooner is he over but the Signal is given: they bolt out of the Houſe, ſtriving who ſhould get firſt in. Coming in that haſt and fury all at once on the Brink they all fell in: <hi>Andrew</hi> ſteps through the <hi>Houſe, leaving them to diſengage themſelves of the Common Shore, and their ſtinking <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nguent.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Tho he has <hi>Thriv'd in this Enterpriſe,</hi> 'tis to be believ'd <hi>That he is not Infallible,</hi> but may miſcarey ſome other time, as the Sequel of the Action to come will demonſtrate. <hi>The</hi> Bailiffs <hi>are Croſs bit,</hi> but now comes his part upon the Stage.</p>
            <p>Croſſing the Fields he met a willing <hi>Pinace</hi> her Rigging Freſh and Serviceable, and the boat ſeemed to ſwim finely <hi>without crying; So ho, to the boats Crew:</hi> he grapples with her; ſhe willing to ſtand the ſame Courſe as he ſtood, tacks and Sayls with him; they put into the moſt convenient Port for their <hi>Traffick;</hi> reſolving to make but a ſhort Voyage.</p>
            <p>They are now in Harbour, where he intends to give himſelf to dalliance, whilſt his Accomplice is as ready as he is urgent. Several indearing expreſſions paſs, they
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:151644:32"/>Imbrace <hi>(only the outward way)</hi> in this <hi>loving</hi> Conflict you will find that they like water Men, look'd the way they were not a <hi>going:</hi> To be brief, ſhe fathom'd the bottom of his Pocket Wealth, for what he then had was his All.</p>
            <p>After this ſhe could deny him nothing, and that which he took for a Singular Favour, and more particular Expreſſion of her warm Affections, was only to conceal the Cheat ſhe had put upon him, <hi>and prevent</hi> his enquiring into the Strength of <hi>his Pock<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2+ letters">
                     <desc>••…</desc>
                  </gap>.</hi> When <hi>Andrew</hi> had drank her as he thought a Note beyond Diſcretion, he was then to play the latter part of the Game, which was to leave her for the Reckoning; and to render his Eſcape leſs ſuſpitious he <hi>wanted</hi> not Excuſe to go out, nor was ſhe <hi>unwilling,</hi> who <hi>thought</hi> it would be a lucky Minute; wherein ſhe ſhould hear that her Gallant was run away from her, and his Purſe; which he accordingly did. She no ſooner found him gone but the houſe is paid, and ſhe betakes her ſelf to Shelter. He had not been as he Imagin'd long in Security, but having an Occaſion to conſult his Poc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kets, with Grief and Amazement he found that his Money was all gone; which put
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:151644:32"/>him into ſuch a frantick Fit, that he runs over all places as a Wild Bull, that thinks himſelf rob'd of his dear Mulls.</p>
            <p>At Nine of the Clock at <hi>Night</hi> he ſtum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles into a <hi>Church Yard,</hi> where <hi>going into the Porch to reſt himſelf,</hi> he ſits down on a Drunken Sea Man, who had lately re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd his Ticket-money; <hi>he was ſomething ſtartled at firſt,</hi> but <hi>being</hi> Fearleſs by Deſpair, he dives into the then dead Mans Treaſure, which was no leſs at that Inſtant; but becauſe it was no Jeſt without doubling his Miſchief, <hi>he took the debauch'd Salt water Fith on his Back,</hi> and carried him to the Church Gate, where ſtood a pair of Stocks, and <hi>putting his Legs into the Holes,</hi> claps down the Top piece, and leaves him, to ſleep himſelf into Freedom, and another Voy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>age.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Having thus clear'd himſelf of his debauch'd Companion,</hi> he reſolves once more to take the Air, and make a Viſit to an old Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaintance of his a Joyners Wife, <hi>who h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d formerly been his Intimate and familiar Friend,</hi> ſhe <hi>living</hi> not above ten Miles from the <hi>City.</hi> Setting forth at break of Day, <hi>that he might</hi> have the Pleaſure of the <hi>Morning,</hi> he <hi>march'd</hi>
               <pb n="58" facs="tcp:151644:33"/>till he came within four <hi>Miles</hi> of the place, when drawing near to a <hi>Houſe of Entertain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> he <hi>calls</hi> for Drink, but there being no body up in the Houſe but a little Girl, ſhe was loth to let him in: So he travels for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward, and <hi>having paſs'd the bounds of a Warren,</hi> it was not <hi>long</hi> e're he came to a Thatch'd Tenement, <hi>where in the Confines of a little Orchard,</hi> his hawks Eye diſcovered a parcel of Poultrey; his Stomach <hi>craving for</hi> Food he reſolves to have a hollow Bit, when taking up a Stone, and <hi>making Advantage of the Hedge,</hi> he turn'd up the Heels of a ſhe Cackler, and <hi>ſitting</hi> down in the bottom of the Ditch he pull'd forth his Knife, and for haſt fleas off both the Skin and Feathers, throwing away all Superfluities, he diſſects every par and ties it up in an old <hi>Handkerchief.</hi> Comeing into the ſame Houſe, <hi>he enquires after his familiar way,</hi> how their Neighborr Handſaw, the Joyners Wife did, <hi>and whether they thought ſhe might be at home?</hi> Yes, ſays the Good Woman; <hi>having ſent a Meſſenger to ſpeak with her, he calls for Drink,</hi> telling his ſilly Hoſteſs that <hi>Travelling</hi> over the Warren he had <hi>bought</hi> a Rabit, deſiring her to lend him her Pan to fry it. The woman would willingly have cook'd it her ſelf, but he deſirous to do it his own way, tells her he
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:151644:33"/>intended a Frigacy; which the <hi>good Countrey Soul underſtood not:</hi> Aſſoon as the Fricacy was ready; in came his old Acquaintance, whom he ſaluted by the Name of Couſin; the <hi>Hoſteſs</hi> little thinking how ſhe was cou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſened by him, they ſit down at the Table where having fed luſtily he drinks to his <hi>Hoſteſs,</hi> Asking of her how ſhe like'<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> his way of dreſſing a Rabbit; very well An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwers the good Wife, I have not Eaten a ſweeter bit. <hi>He</hi> finding no Opportunity there to renew his former Acquaintance with his Cozen, diſcharges die Reckoning and goes home with her to her own houſe, Carrying a Pitcher of Liquor with them that they might have no Occaſion to ſend out. Being merrily diſpoſed and their Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petites heightned by the late ſtollen Colla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, they begin to make uſe of what Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture gave them, The Good Man her <hi>Huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band</hi> who was hard at Work abroad, little thought that his Wife was Cornuting him at home, but it being now <hi>Twelve</hi> returns to Dinner; and knocking earneſtly at the Door put the Lovers into a Fit of an Ague, She neither knowing where to Conceale him, or he how to Eſcape. As a Womans Wit is always good at a Pinch, ſhe claps him up the Chimney, and goes to the door,
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:151644:34" rendition="simple:additions"/>where ſhe receives her <hi>Husband</hi> with a flat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering Smile, whilſt he poſts to the Cup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>board, and finding ſome Porridge <hi>reſolves</hi> to heat 'em for his Dinner, Scolding and Curſing his Wife for not making a Fire. Haſting to his Work houſe, he <hi>brings</hi> an Arm full of Shavings, and with the Candle ſet them a blazeing. <hi>Andrew</hi> finding his Shoes begin to fry and his Legs ſcorch, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiders it was better to be well Cudgelled for his Lecherous Deſigns, than ſtay there and be burn'd. Thus reſolved, he jumps down, and not ſeeing which way he went, fell with one Leg into the Porridge. The poor Man ſeeing this party Coloured Ghoſt, flyes out of the Doors, his Wife after him, telling him it was a juſt Judgmen upon him for Curſing and Swearing. Whilſt theſe Two were Arguing, <hi>Merry Andrew</hi> made his Eſcape at the Back-door, over joyed at his ſo happy Deliverance. <hi>Where I ſhall now leave him to purſue his Rambling Phancy.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:151644:34"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
